We are independent & ad-supported. We may earn a commission for purchases made through our links. Learn more.

* Join Newsletter

*  Explore
*  About
* Join Newsletter

Advertiser Disclosure

Our website is an independent, advertising-supported platform. We provide our content free of charge to our readers, and to keep it that way, we rely on revenue generated through advertisements and affiliate partnerships. This means that when you click on certain links on our site and make a purchase, we may earn a commission. [Learn more.](https://www.wise-geek.com/how-we-make-money.htm)

How We Make Money

We sustain our operations through affiliate commissions and advertising. If you click on an affiliate link and make a purchase, we may receive a commission from the merchant at no additional cost to you. We also display advertisements on our website, which help generate revenue to support our work and keep our content free for readers. Our editorial team operates independently of our advertising and affiliate partnerships to ensure that our content remains unbiased and focused on providing you with the best information and recommendations based on thorough research and honest evaluations. To remain transparent, we’ve provided a list of our current affiliate partners [here.](https://www.wise-geek.com/how-we-make-money.htm#our-partners)

Advertisement - scroll for more content

WiseGeek's Privacy Policy
=========================

Updated: May 21, 2024

Views: 1,022,759

We take our user's privacy very seriously. If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please [contact us](https://www.wise-geek.com/contact.htm).

WiseGeek is wholly owned and operated by Conjecture Corporation.

By using WiseGeek content, you accept our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.wise-geek.com/what-are-terms-and-conditions.htm) which includes this Privacy Policy. If you do not want to be bound by WiseGeek’s Privacy Policy, or Terms and Conditions, your only remedy is to stop using WiseGeek’s content.

Information Sharing
-------------------

WiseGeek takes the privacy of our visitors very seriously. WiseGeek does not share the information it collects, whether general or personal, in any specific way with third parties without visitor consent or as otherwise required by law.

WiseGeek may collect (1) personal or (2) general visitor-related information:

### (1) Personal Information Including Email Addresses

WiseGeek will never sell, lease or share personal information, including names and email addresses, with any third party.

Visitors will not be required to provide personal information for ordinary use of the site. Visitors may have the opportunity to provide WiseGeek with their personal information in response to specific services or tasks (e.g., signing up for WiseGeek's newsletter). In order to receive additional services, visitors may be required to provide personal information such as names and email addresses.

### (2) General Information

Like many other web sites, WiseGeek tracks general information tied to our visitors to enhance our visitors’ experiences by analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking user’s movement around the site, and gathering demographic information. This information that is tracked, also referred to as log files, includes but is not limited to, internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser types, Internet Service Providers (ISPs), access times, referring web sites, exit pages, and click activity. This information that is tracked does not identify a visitor personally (e.g., by name).

One way WiseGeek collects this general information is through cookies, a small text file with a unique identifying string of characters. Cookies help WiseGeek store information about visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information about the pages users access, and customize web content based on a visitor’s browser type or other information that the visitor sends through their browser.

You can disable cookies in your web browser so that cookies are not set without your permission. Note that disabling cookies, may limit the features and services available to you. The cookies that WiseGeek sets are not tied to any personal information. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites.

### Other Sites

WiseGeek’s Privacy Policy only applies to WiseGeek content. Other websites, including those that advertise on WiseGeek, link to WiseGeek, or that WiseGeek links to, may have their own policies.

When you click on these ads or links, these third party advertisers or sites automatically receive your IP address. Other technologies, like cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons, may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

WiseGeek has no control over, and is not responsible for, the ways these other websites collect or use your information. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more information on their practices as well as for instructions on how to opt-out of certain practices.

Google's DoubleClick DART Cookies
---------------------------------

As a third party advertising vendor, Google will place a DART cookie on your computer when you visit a site using DoubleClick or Google AdSense advertising. Google uses this cookie to serve ads specific to you and your interests. The ads shown may be targeted based on your previous browsing history. DART cookies only use non-personally identifiable information. They _do not_ track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You may prevent Google from using DART cookies on your computer by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx).

Affiliate Program Participation
-------------------------------

WiseGeek is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites. Through Amazon Associates Program, the Website will provide customized links provided by Amazon to track referrals to their website. Cookies are used by this program to track visits so that commissions can be assigned on sales.

WiseGeek is a participant in other affiliate advertising programs through such companies as Share A Sale, CJ.com and others. Through these affiliate programs, the Website will provide customized links provided by the affiliate programs to track referrals to their websites. Cookies are used by these programs to track visits so that commissions can be assigned on sales.

Mediavine Programmatic Advertising (Ver 1.1)
--------------------------------------------

The Website works with Mediavine to manage third-party interest-based advertising appearing on the Website. Mediavine serves content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use first and third-party cookies. A cookie is a small text file which is sent to your computer or mobile device (referred to in this policy as a “device”) by the web server so that a website can remember some information about your browsing activity on the Website.

First party cookies are created by the website that you are visiting. A third-party cookie is frequently used in behavioral advertising and analytics and is created by a domain other than the website you are visiting. Third-party cookies, tags, pixels, beacons and other similar technologies (collectively, “Tags”) may be placed on the Website to monitor interaction with advertising content and to target and optimize advertising. Each internet browser has functionality so that you can block both first and third-party cookies and clear your browser’s cache. The "help" feature of the menu bar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to receive notification of new cookies, how to disable existing cookies and how to clear your browser’s cache. For more information about cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information at [All About Cookies](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/).

Without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of the Website content and features. Please note that rejecting cookies does not mean that you will no longer see ads when you visit our Site. In the event you opt-out, you will still see non-personalized advertisements on the Website.

The Website collects the following data using a cookie when serving personalized ads:

* IP Address
* Operating System type
* Operating System version
* Device Type
* Language of the website
* Web browser type
* Email (in hashed form)

Mediavine Partners (companies listed below with whom Mediavine shares data) may also use this data to link to other end user information the partner has independently collected to deliver targeted advertisements. Mediavine Partners may also separately collect data about end users from other sources, such as advertising IDs or pixels, and link that data to data collected from Mediavine publishers in order to provide interest-based advertising across your online experience, including devices, browsers and apps. This data includes usage data, cookie information, device information, information about interactions between users and advertisements and websites, geolocation data, traffic data, and information about a visitor’s referral source to a particular website. Mediavine Partners may also create unique IDs to create audience segments, which are used to provide targeted advertising.

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices to opt-in or opt-out of this data collection, please visit [National Advertising Initiative opt out page](https://thenai.org/opt-out/). You may also visit [Digital Advertising Alliance website](http://optout.aboutads.info/#/) and [Network Advertising Initiative website](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) to learn more information about interest-based advertising. You may download the AppChoices app at [Digital Advertising Alliance’s AppChoices app](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices) to opt out in connection with mobile apps, or use the platform controls on your mobile device to opt out.

For specific information about Mediavine Partners, the data each collects and their data collection and privacy policies, please visit [Mediavine Partners](https://www.mediavine.com/ad-partners/).

Policy Changes
--------------

Please note that we may change our Privacy Policy from time to time. Users can view our latest Privacy Policy at any time by visiting: [/what-is-the-privacy-policy.htm](https://www.wise-geek.com/what-is-the-privacy-policy.htm)

Contact Us
----------

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, feel free to [contact us](https://www.wise-geek.com/contact.htm) by email, or in writing to the following address:

Conjecture Corporation  
re: WiseGeek Privacy Policy  
PO Box 2130  
Sparks, NV 89432  
U.S.A.

_This page was last updated on May 21, 2024._

On this page

On this page

╳

1. [Information Sharing](#274bat693lj4oc8g8o8wc0gsw)
2. [Google's DoubleClick DART Cookies](#1f9lc20x456sgckk0484k4k04)
3. [Affiliate Program Participation](#3xrjl8m4zco4o4o4s84woocwg)
4. [Mediavine Programmatic Advertising (Ver 1.1)](#adu8lu9a0qo0c4wog4sck8cwk)
5. [Policy Changes](#7v8zi249urcwg8s8kww0gswoc)
6. [Contact Us](#9al0nbqp56w4occk80scg8scc)

Prev Next

Share

On this page

Jump to

Share

https://www.wise-geek.com/what-is-the-privacy-policy.htm

WiseGeek, in your inbox

Our latest articles, guides, and more, delivered daily.

 Subscribe

Categories

Get Around

Find Us

Copyright 2003 - 2024 [Conjecture Corporation](https://conjecture.com/)

WiseGeek, in your inbox

Our latest articles, guides, and more, delivered daily.

  Subscribe
